大家好 今天给大家介绍一部2016年的中国电影
hi guys today I will introduce a Chinese movie in 2016
叫七月与安生
it is called Qi yue and An sheng
七月和安生是电影的两个女主角
Qi yue and An sheng are the leading roles in this movie
七月呢 是一个生活在幸福家庭的乖乖女
Qi yue is a good girl living in a happy family
安生 是一个生活在不幸福家庭的叛逆女孩
An sheng is a rebellious girl living in an unhappy family
但是她们两个是非常亲密的好朋友
but they are best friends
ok now it is about Qi yue has a crush on a boy
好 然后现在我们看一下七月喜欢上了一个男生
然后呢 她把这件事情告诉了安生
and she told An sheng about this
好 我们还是先看一下词汇
ok let us take a look at the some words firstly
第一个是 一辈子注定四海为家
the first one: be doomed to travel around in one's life
一辈子的意思就是一生
this word means a lifetime
四海为家的意思就是在哪里都可以生活
this word means make one's home
都可以稳定下来
wherever one is
然后下一个是 厚实的臂弯
and next one strong arms
因为男生的手臂一般 都比较粗 比较结实
because usually the arms of the guys tend to be stronger
然后呢 女生躺在那里会比较有安全感
and therefore girls feel secure when they lie down there
所以当我们在说 厚实的臂弯
so when we are talking about strong arms
我们一般说的是男生
we are usually indicating the males
下一个期中 期末
next one midterm and the end of term
在中国的学校里 一个学期会有很多次考试
in China's schools  there are a lot of exams in every semester
但是最重要的一般是期末考试
but usually the final exam matters most
然后另外一个比较重要的就是 期中考试
and the midterm exam is the second one which matters
下一个是缘分
next one "fate"
缘分这个词 英语里边可能没有完全对应的
there is not an English word which exactly matches this Chinese word
但是它的意思是 比如说
the meaning is like
你很喜欢一个人 然后她也喜欢你
when you have a crush on someone and she likes you as well
然后你发现你每天都能碰到她
and you find you bump into her every day
你就可以告诉她 我觉得我们很有缘分
then you can say to her that you think fate brings us together
下一个是 谈恋爱
next one to be in a relationship
谈恋爱是一个动词
this is a verb
我们会说 谈+恋爱
it is actually like "to talk" "in the relationship"
因为我们觉得在一个恋爱关系里边
because we think when we are in a relationship
我们要说很多话
usually we talk a lot
下一个是难忍
next one unbearable
这个词其实她 说的是难以忍受
it is from the word "hard to bear"
在这个片段里 七月告诉安生她有喜欢的人了
in this clip  Qi yue told An sheng about her crush
安生有点儿失落
Ansheng felt a bit sad
因为她觉得她最好的朋友 可能以后不会那么需要她
because she thought her best friend no longer needs her that much as before
但是不管怎么说
but no matter how she feels
七月还是跟那个他喜欢的男生在一起了
Qi yue and that guy ended up together
after graduating from the university  Qi yue found a job in a local bank
毕业了之后 七月去了当地的银行工作
这个做法非常地中国人
it is very typical Chinese
因为 很多中国的家长希望自己的孩子去银行工作
because many Chinese parents think working in a bank
或者说去当老师
or a school is great
他们觉得这样的工作很稳定
as people uausally don't get fired there
但是呢 喜欢流浪的安生却去了北京
however An sheng went to Beijing as she likes to travel around
后来七月的男朋友也去了北京
and then Qi yue's boyfriend went to Beijing as well
七月的男朋友看起来是一个很听话的男生
he looks like an obedient guy
但是我觉得他的心里也有叛逆的地方
but I believe he has the rebellious side as well
而且从第一次七月的男朋友见到安生 他就很喜欢安生
actually he had feelings for An sheng at the first sight
因为安生和七月是两个非常不一样的女孩子
because An sheng and Qi yue are very different
安生是一个非常自由热情的女孩子
An sheng is free and passionate
然后因为安生和七月的男朋友都在北京
An sheng and Qi yue's boyfriend both lived in Beijing
所以不出意料地 七月的男朋友背叛了七月
so unsurprisingly he was cheating on Qiyue by sleeping with An sheng
七月发现了之后 我们看一下七月和安生有什么样的对话
Qi yue found out that and let us see what she says to An sheng
好 我们还是先看一下生词
ok let us look at the new words firstly
第一个 痛快
first word "to one's great satisfaction"
痛快的意思就是爽
this word has the similar meaning to "shuang"
比如说 周五的晚上我们可以喝酒喝个痛快
like on Friday night you can drink your fill
因为周六不上班
because you don't have to go to work on Saturday
或者说周六的时候可以睡觉睡个痛快
or you can sleep in on Saturday
因为反正也不用工作嘛
as you don't have to work anyway
下一个是 今天喝的酒白喝了
next one I wasted the alcohol (because she vomited)
白然后一个动词的意思就是
"bai" together with a verb
你做了也没有用
means something is in vain
比如说你做了一个工作
if you did a something in you work
可是你的老板说不行 你要重新做
but your boss told you to do it all over again
那你就可以说 这个工作白做了
then you can say all my work was wasted
下一个是自欺欺人
next one means to deceive oneself as well as others
自欺就是欺骗自己
"zi qi" means to deceive oneself
欺人就是欺骗别人
"qi ren" means to deceive others
所以这个词的意思是不仅欺骗自己 而且欺骗别人
that is why it means not only deceive oneself also deceive others
下一个是资格 有资格 和 没有资格
next one to be entitled to or to be not entitled to
比如说如果你的伴侣看你的手机
if your partner checked your cellphone
你可以说你没有资格看我的手机
you can tell your partner that you are not entitled to check my cellphone
这一段是  七月发现了自己最好的朋友背叛了自己
in this clip  Qi yue found her best friend betrayed her
非常愤怒的一段话
said something with anger
首先她讽刺安生说
firstly she was being sarcastic
你以前不是不喜欢穿内衣吗
she pointed that Ansheng used to not wear bras
你就是因为跟我的男朋友在一起才开始穿内衣
but because she thought her boyfriend likes it so she started to wear that
不过呢你失策了
however she was not smart
因为我的男朋友 你并不了解他
because she doesn't really know him well
他其实不喜欢好看的内衣
he actually prefer the old fashioned bras
他就是很喜欢很土的内衣
than the fancy ones
在这里她想向安生证明
here Qi yue is trying to prove
她才是了解她男朋友的那个人
she knows her boyfriend better
然后她还提到从小到大都是她给了安生很多东西
and then she mentioned that she gave An sheng many things since they were kids
所以安生说 她要把她的男朋友让给她的时候
so when An sheng said that she would let Qi yue take back her boyfriend
她说 她没有资格
Qi yue said she is not entitled to say that
所以七月最后和她的男朋友复合了吗
so does Qi yue get back with her boyfriend in the end?
七月和安生从此就绝交了吗
Qi yue and An sheng just stopped talking since then?
如果你们感兴趣的话
if you are interested to find out
可以去看一下这部电影
you can watch the complete movie
虽然这部电影的情节很普通
the story of this movie is quite plain
但是里边的主角说的都是标准的普通话
but at least they are speaking standard Mandarin
所以作为汉语学习材料的话 还是不错的
so it can be a good one for practicing Chinese
因为中国有太多电影说的是方言了 非常不适合学习
because there are many Chinese movies speaking dialects which are not suitbale for Chinese learning
欢迎你们留言告诉我 你是否喜欢今天的视频
welcome to leave your comments to tell me if you like this video or not
如果喜欢的话 记得 点赞 订阅 还有转发哦
if you do like it  don't forget to like subscribe and repost
谢谢你们 下期见
thank you and I will see you next time